<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SOAP | Jacob Weaver]]></title>
  <link href="http://jweaver.me/blog/categories/soap/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jweaver.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-19T10:31:34-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jweaver.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jacob Weaver]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Laravel is a great framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://jweaver.me/blog/2014/02/16/laravel-is-a-great-framework/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-16T09:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jweaver.me/blog/2014/02/16/laravel-is-a-great-framework</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently had to work on a project that required hooking into Magento&rsquo;s SOAP API and parsing orders from an Excel spreadsheet into
the Magento dashboard. Although Magento has a REST API, it doesn&rsquo;t seem to be nearly as capable as the SOAP API, and offers no real
functionality other than the ability to get orders, products, and so on.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Having never really worked with a SOAP API, I went to my usual framework (Ruby on Rails) and looked for a SOAP gem. I found
<a href="http://savonrb.com/">Savon</a> and thought I would give that a shot. While Savon works for most applications, something about
the way Magento was requiring the request body to be formatted wasn&rsquo;t jiving with how Savon wanted to format it for me.</p>

<h3>Laravel to the Rescue</h3>

<hr />

<p>I decided that I would have to use PHP for this, since PHP has support for SOAP built right in, and also because all of the examples
Magento gave on their site were for PHP. Creating a soap client in PHP is as simple as:
<code>php
$client = new SoapClient('your-wsdl-here');
</code>
And from there I was able to use the Magento API as documented. Now this doesn&rsquo;t really pertain to Laravel, just PHP in general. But
where Laravel comes in handy is the rest of the application. I&rsquo;ve attempted to learn Laravel in the past (version 3) and wasn&rsquo;t that
into it. Maybe it was just that I wasn&rsquo;t dedicated to it, but I feel that the framework has come a long way in version 4. Routes and
Controllers are incredibly easy to use, and setting them up in a RESTful way is very simple. For example, if you have a Post resource,
then a simple route like this:
<code>php
Route::resource('posts', 'PostsController');
</code>
will link to a controller and automatically accept standard RESTful actions:
```php
public function index()
{</p>

<pre><code>return View::make('posts.index');
</code></pre>

<p>}</p>

<p>public function create()
{</p>

<pre><code>return View::make('posts.create');
</code></pre>

<p>}
```
and so on. This made building the rest of my application incredibly easy, and the native SOAP support in PHP was simple to use as well.
I&rsquo;ll be using Laravel on future projects, for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
